{"test_questions": [[{"question": "(17)3.5 x (17)? = 178", "opta": "2.29", "optb": "2.75", "optc": "4.25", "optd": "4.5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Let (17)3.5 x (17)x = 178.\nThen, (17)3.5 + x = 178.\n 3.5 + x = 8\n x = (8 - 3.5)\n x = 4.5"}, {"question": "If\n\na\n\nx - 1\n=\n\nb\n\nx - 3\n, then the value of x is:\n\n\nb\na", "opta": "1\n\n\n2", "optb": "2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Given \na\n\nx - 1\n=\n\nb\n\nx - 3\n\n\nb\na\n\n\n\n\n\n\n \n\na\n\nx - 1\n=\n\na\n\n-(x - 3)\n\u00a0=\u00a0\n\na\n\n(3 - x)\n\n\nb\nb\nb\n\n\n\n x - 1 = 3 - x\n 2x = 4\n x = 2."}, {"question": "Given that 100.48 = x, 100.70 = y and xz = y2, then the value of z is close to:", "opta": "1.45", "optb": "1.88", "optc": "2.9", "optd": "3.7", "ans": "C", "explanation": "xz = y2 \u00a0\u00a0  \u00a0\u00a0 10(0.48z) = 10(2 x 0.70) = 101.40\n 0.48z = 1.40\n\n\n\n z =\n140\n=\n35\n= 2.9 (approx.)\n\n\n48\n12"}, {"question": "If 5a = 3125, then the value of 5(a - 3) is:", "opta": "25", "optb": "125", "optc": "625", "optd": "1625", "ans": "A", "explanation": "5a = 3125 \u00a0\u00a0  \u00a0\u00a0 5a = 55\n a = 5.\n 5(a - 3) = 5(5 - 3) = 52 = 25."}, {"question": "If 3(x - y) = 27 and 3(x + y) = 243, then x is equal to:", "opta": "0", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "3x - y = 27 = 33 \u00a0\u00a0  \u00a0\u00a0 x - y = 3 ....(i)\n3x + y = 243 = 35 \u00a0\u00a0  \u00a0\u00a0 x + y = 5 ....(ii)\nOn solving (i) and (ii), we get x = 4."}, {"question": "(256)0.16 x (256)0.09 = ?", "opta": "4", "optb": "16", "optc": "64", "optd": "256.25", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(256)0.16 x (256)0.09 = (256)(0.16 + 0.09)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (256)0.25\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (256)(25/100)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (256)(1/4)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (44)(1/4)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 44(1/4)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 41\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 4"}, {"question": "The value of [(10)150 \u00f7 (10)146]", "opta": "1000", "optb": "10000", "optc": "100000", "optd": "106", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(10)150 \u00f7 (10)146 =\n10150\n\n\n10146\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 10150 - 146\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 104\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 10000."}, {"question": "1\u00a0\n+\n1\n+\n1\n= ?\n\n\n1 + x(b - a) + x(c - a)\n1 + x(a - b) + x(c - b)\n1 + x(b - c) + x(a - c)", "opta": "0", "optb": "1", "optc": "xa - b - c", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Given Exp. =\n\n\n\n1\n\u00a0+\u00a0\n1\n\u00a0+\u00a0\n1\n\n\n\n\n\n1 +\nxb\n+\nxc\n\n\n\nxa\nxa\n\n\n\n\n\n1 +\nxa\n+\nxc\n\n\n\nxb\nxb\n\n\n\n\n\n1 +\nxb\n+\nxa\n\n\n\nxc\nxc\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 =\nxa\n+\nxb\n+\nxc\n\n\n(xa + xb + xc)\n(xa + xb + xc)\n(xa + xb + xc)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 =\n(xa + xb + xc)\n\n\n(xa + xb + xc)\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 1."}, {"question": "(25)7.5 x (5)2.5 \u00f7 (125)1.5 = 5?", "opta": "8.5", "optb": "13", "optc": "16", "optd": "17.5", "opte": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Let (25)7.5 x (5)2.5 \u00f7 (125)1.5 = 5x.\n\n\n\nThen,\n(52)7.5 x (5)2.5\n= 5x\n\n\n(53)1.5\n\n\n\n\n\n\n \n5(2 x 7.5) x 52.5\n= 5x\n\n\n5(3 x 1.5)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n \n515 x 52.5\n= 5x\n\n\n54.5\n\n\n\n 5x = 5(15 + 2.5 - 4.5)\n 5x = 513\n x = 13."}, {"question": "(0.04)-1.5 = ?", "opta": "25", "optb": "125", "optc": "250", "optd": "625", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(0.04)-1.5 = \n\n4\n\n-1.5\n\n\n100\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 =\n\n1\n\n-(3/2)\n\n\n25\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (25)(3/2)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (52)(3/2)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (5)2 x (3/2)\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 53\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 125."}, {"question": "(243)n/5 x 32n + 1 \n= ?\n\n\n9n x 3n - 1", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "9", "optd": "3n", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Given Expression\n\n\n\n=\n(243)(n/5) x 32n + 1\n\n\n9n x 3n - 1\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n(35)(n/5) x 32n + 1\n\n\n(32)n x 3n - 1\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n(35 x (n/5) x 32n + 1)\n\n\n(32n x 3n - 1)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n3n x 32n + 1\n\n\n32n x 3n - 1\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n3(n + 2n + 1)\n\n\n3(2n + n - 1)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n=\n33n + 1\n\n\n33n - 1\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n= 3(3n + 1 - 3n + 1) \u00a0\u00a0= 32 \u00a0\u00a0= 9."}, {"question": "1\n+\n1\n= ?\n\n\n1 + a(n - m)\n1 + a(m - n)", "opta": "0", "optb": "1\n\n\n2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "1\n+\n1\n=\n\n\n\n1\n\u00a0+\u00a0\n1\n\n\n\n\n\n1 +\nan\n\n\n\nam\n\n\n\n\n\n1 +\nam\n\n\n\nan\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n1 + a(n - m)\n1 + a(m - n)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 =\nam\n+\nan\n\n\n(am + an)\n(am + an)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 =\n(am + an)\n\n\n(am + an)\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 1."}, {"question": "If m and n are whole numbers such that mn = 121, the value of (m - 1)n + 1 is:", "opta": "1", "optb": "10", "optc": "121", "optd": "1000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "We know that 112 = 121.\nPutting m = 11 and n = 2, we get:\n(m - 1)n + 1 = (11 - 1)(2 + 1) = 103  = 1000."}, {"question": "xb\n\n(b + c - a)\n.\n\nxc\n\n(c + a - b)\n.\n\nxa\n\n(a + b - c)\n= ?\n\n\nxc\nxa\nxb", "opta": "xabc", "optb": "1", "optc": "xab + bc + ca", "optd": "xa + b + c", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Given Exp.\n\n\n\n= x(b - c)(b + c - a) . x(c - a)(c + a - b) . x(a - b)(a + b - c)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n= x(b - c)(b + c) - a(b - c)\u00a0\u00a0.\u00a0\u00a0x(c - a)(c + a) - b(c - a)\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0.\u00a0\u00a0x(a - b)(a + b) - c(a - b)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n= x(b2 - c2 + c2 - a2 + a2 - b2)\u00a0\u00a0.\u00a0\u00a0 x-a(b - c) - b(c - a) - c(a - b)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n= (x0 x x0)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n= (1 x 1) = 1."}, {"question": "If x = 3 + 22, then the value of\n\nx\n-\n1\n\nis:\n\n\nx", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "22", "optd": "33", "ans": "B", "explanation": "x\n-\n1\n\n2\n= x +\n1\n- 2\n\n\nx\nx\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (3 + 22) +\n1\n- 2\n\n\n(3 + 22)\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (3 + 22) +\n1\nx\n(3 - 22)\n- 2\n\n\n(3 + 22)\n(3 - 22)\n\n\n\n\u00a0\u00a0 = (3 + 22) + (3 - 22) - 2\n\u00a0\u00a0 = 4.\n\n\n\n \n\nx\n-\n1\n\n= 2.\n\n\nx"}]]}